Guide to the Divinity School Records, circa 1920-2005 UA.19.01.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Administrative Files, circa 1920-2005; 156 Linear Feet; 109 boxes
  - School of Religion Files
    - General Correspondence, 1931 June (2 folders) (Box 99)
    - General Correspondence, 1931 July (2 folders) (Box 99)
    - General Correspondence, 1931 Aug. (2 folders) (Box 99)
    - General Correspondence, 1931 Sept. (3 folders) (Box 99)
    - General Correspondence, 1931 Oct. (3 folders) (Box 99)
    - General Correspondence, 1931 Nov. (Box 99)
    - General Correspondence, 1931 Dec. (Box 99)
    - Correspondence concerning the minutes of the American Methodist Episcopal Conference, 1932 (2 folders) (Box 99)
    - Correspondence concerning the minutes of the American Methodist Episcopal Conference, 1932 (4 folders) (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: A, 1932 (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: B, 1932 (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: C-E, 1932 (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: F-G, 1932 (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: H-I, 1932 (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: K-L, 1932 (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: M-N, 1932 (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: P-R, 1932 (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: S-V, 1932 (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: W-Z, 1932 (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: A-B, 1933 (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: C-E, 1933 (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: F-J, 1933 (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: K-R, 1933 (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: S-Z, 1933 (2 of 3 folders) (Box 100)
    - General Correspondence: S-Z, 1933 (Box 101)
    - Guilford College: General Information, 1933 (Box 101)
    - Duke Endowment Christmas Checks, 1933 (Box 101)
    - General Correspondence: A, 1934 (Box 101)
    - General Correspondence: B, 1934 (3 folders) (Box 101)
    - General Correpsondence: C, 1934 (4 folders) (Box 101)
    - General Correspondence: D-E, 1934 (2 folders) (Box 101)
    - General Correspondence: F-G, 1934 (3 folders) (Box 101)
    - General Correspondence: H, 1934 (3 folders) (Box 101)
    - General Correspondence: J-L, 1934 (3 folders) (Box 101)
    - General Correspondence: M, 1934 (Box 101)
    - General Correspondence: P-Q, 1934 (Box 101)
    - Junaluska School of Religion, 1934 (Box 101)
    - Methodist Episcopal Church: Conference Correspondence, 1934 (Box 101)
    - Methodist Episcopal Church: Conference Correspondence, 1935 (Box 101)
    - General Correspondence, 1935 Jan.-Feb. (2 folders) (Box 101)
    - General Correspondence, 1935 March-April (2 folders) (Box 101)
    - General Correspondence, 1935 May-June (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - General Correspondence, 1935 July-Aug. (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - General Correspondence, 1935 Sept.-Oct. (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - General Correspondence, 1935 Nov.-Dec. (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - Dedication of the Chapel, 1935 June (Box 102)
    - General Correspondence, 1936 Jan. (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - General Correspondence, 1936 Feb. (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - General Correspondence, 1936 March (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - General Correspondence, 1936 April (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - General Correspondence, 1936 May (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - General Correspondence, 1936 June (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - General Correspondence, 1936 July (Box 102)
    - General Correspondence, 1936 Aug. (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - General Correspondence, 1936 Sept. (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - General Correspondence, 1936 Oct. (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - General Correspondence, 1936 Nov.-Dec. (2 folders) (Box 103)
    - Inquiries Concerning Types of Extension Work in Southeastern Seminars, 1937 (Box 103)
    - General Correspondence: A-B, 1937 (3 folders) (Box 103)
    - General Correspondence: C, 1937 (2 folders) (Box 103)
    - General Correspondence: E-F, 1937 (Box 103)
    - General Correspondence: G-I, 1937 (2 folders) (Box 103)
    - General Correspondence: J-M, 1937 (2 folders) (Box 103)
    - General Correspondence: N-R, 1937 (2 folders) (Box 103)
    - General Correspondence: S-Z, 1937 (2 folders) (Box 103)
    - The Methodist Meeting House, 1938 (Box 103)
    - General Correspondence: A-F, 1938 (Box 103)
    - General Correspondence: G, 1938 (3 folders) (Box 103)
    - General Correspondence: H-J, 1938 (Box 103)
    - General Correspondence: K-M, 1938 (3 folders) (Box 103)
    - General Correspondence: N-R, 1938 (2 folders) (Box 104)
    - General Correspondence: S, 1938 (3 folders) (Box 104)
    - General Correspondence: T, 1938 (Box 104)
    - General Correspondence: W-Z, 1938 (3 folders) (Box 104)
    - General Correspondence: A-B, 1939 (3 folders) (Box 104)
    - General Correspondence: B, 1939 (2 folders) (Box 104)
    - General Correspondence: C, 1939 (2 folders) (Box 104)
    - General Correspondence: D, 1939 (Box 104)
    - General Correspondence: E-F, 1939 (2 folders) (Box 104)
    - General Correspondence: G, 1939 (3 folders) (Box 104)
    - General Correspondence: H-I, 1939 (Box 104)
    - General Correspondence, J-K, 1939 (2 folders) (Box 104)
    - General Correspondence: L-M 1939 (1 of 2 folders) (Box 104)
    - General Correspondence: L-M, 1939 (Box 105)
    - General Correspondence: M, 1939 (Box 105)
    - General Correspondence: N-Q, 1939 (3 folders) (Box 105)
    - General Correspondence: R, 1939 (2 folders) (Box 105)
    - General Correspondence: S, 1939 (5 folders) (Box 105)
    - General Correspondence: T, 1939 (Box 105)
    - General Correspondence: U-Z, 1939 (2 folders) (Box 105)
    - General Correspondence: A, 1940 (2 folders) (Box 105)
    - General Correspondence: B, 1940 (4 folders) (Box 105)
    - General Correspondence: C, 1940 (4 folders) (Box 105)
    - General Correspondence: D, 1940 (2 folders) (Box 105)
    - General Correspondence: E, 1940 (Box 106)
    - General Correspondence: F, 1940 (Box 106)
    - General Correspondence: G, 1940 (2 folders) (Box 106)
    - General Correspondence: H, 1940 (Box 106)
    - General Correspondence: I-L, 1940 (Box 106)
    - General Correspondence: M-P, 1940 (2 folders) (Box 106)
    - General Correspondence: Q-S, 1940 (2 folders) (Box 106)
    - General Correspondence: T-Z, 1940 (2 folders) (Box 106)
    - General Correspondence: A, 1941 (3 folders) (Box 106)
    - General Correspondence: B, 1941 (4 folders) (Box 106)
    - General Correspondence: C, 1941 (4 folders) (Box 106)
    - General Correspondence: D, 1941 (2 folders) (Box 106)
    - General Correspondence: E, 1941 (Box 106)
    - General Correspondence: F, 1941 (Box 106)
    - General Correspondence: G, 1941 (1 of 2 folders) (Box 106)
    - General Correspondence: G, 1941 (Box 107)
    - General Correspondence: H, 1941 (4 folders) (Box 107)
    - General Correspondence: I-K, 1941 (2 folders) (Box 107)
    - General Correspondence: L-Mc, 1941 (2 folders) (Box 107)
    - General Correspondence: M, 1941 (2 folders) (Box 107)
    - General Correspondence: N-O, 1941 (Box 107)
    - General Correspondence: P-Q, 1941 (2 folders) (Box 107)
    - General Correspondence: R, 1941 (Box 107)
    - General Correspondence: S, 1941 (4 folders) (Box 107)
    - General Correspondence: T-V, 1941 (2 folders) (Box 107)
    - General Correspondence: W, 1941 (Box 107)
    - General Corresponence: W-Z, 1941 (Box 107)
  - Accession A74-43
    - Correspondence: Paul Garber, 1940-1942 (Box 107)
    - Correspondence: Paul Garber, 1943 (Box 107)
  - Accession UA2012-0058
    - Faculty By-Laws, 1991-1997 (Box 112)
  - Accession UA2014.0061, 1964-2010; UA2014.0061; 5 Linear Feet
    Scope and Contents
    This series contains materials from the Dean's Office of the Divinity School. Included are strategic planning documents; self-study documents; minutes from the meetings of several Divinity School groups, especially the Curriculum Committee, the Divinity School Council, and the Faculty Committee; and alphabetical files on events, courses, policies, and operations of the Divinity School.
    Many of the materials in this series are restricted. Administrative files are restricted for a period of 25 years from creation. Files from the Curriculum Committee, Faculty Committee, and Divinity School Council have been restricted for 70 years from creation due to FERPA (Family Educational Rights and Privileges Act) regulations and Duke policies on personnel records.
    - Report of Self-Study, December 1983 (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - "Five Year Plan, Ten Year Vision" Planning Document, March 2 1987 (Box 113, Folder 2)
    - Strategic Plan for the Divinity School, 1992 (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - Report of Self-Study with Strategic Plan and Appenices, December 1993 (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - Self-Study Committee, 1992-1993; 3 folders (Box 113, Folder 5-7)
    - Self-Study Committee, 1992-1994; 3 folders (Box 113, Folder 8-10)
    - Strategic Plans (1 of 3), 2000-2010 (Box 113, Folder 11)
      Conditions Governing Access note
      Access restricted until 2035
    - Strategic Plans (2 of 3), 2000-2010 (Box 113, Folder 12)
    - Strategic Plans (3 of 3), 2000-2010 (Box 113, Folder 13)
    - Strategic Plans, 2000-2010, Items Separated (Box 113, Folder 14)
      Access restricted until 2051
    - ThD, STD Study (1 of 2), 1985-1987 (Box 113, Folder 15)
    - Faculty minutes, 1964-1965 (Box 113, Folder 16)
    - Faculty minutes, 1966-1967 (Box 113, Folder 17)
    - Faculty minutes, 1967-1968 (Box 113, Folder 18)
    - Faculty minutes, 1968-1969 (Box 113, Folder 19)
      Access restricted until 2039
    - Faculty minutes, 1974 (Box 113, Folder 20)
      Access restricted until 2044
    - Faculty minutes, 1975 (Box 113, Folder 21)
      Access restricted until 2045
    - Faculty minutes, 1976 (Box 113, Folder 22)
      Access restricted until 2046
    - Faculty minutes, 1977 (Box 113, Folder 23)
      Access restricted until 2047
    - Faculty minutes, 1978 (Box 113, Folder 24)
      Access restricted until 2048
    - Faculty minutes, 1990-1995 (Box 113, Folder 25)
      Access restricted until 2065
    - Council meeting minutes, 1997-1999 (Box 113, Folder 26)
      Access restricted until 2069
    - Divinity School Council, 1997 (Box 113, Folder 27)
      Access restricted until 2067
    - Divinity School Council, 1998 (Box 113, Folder 28)
      Access restricted until 2068
    - Divinity School Council, 1999 (Box 114, Folder 1)
    - Divinity School Council, 2000 (Box 114, Folder 2)
      Access restricted until 2070
    - Divinity School Council, 2001 (Box 114, Folder 3)
      Access restricted until 2071
    - Divinity School Council, 2002 (Box 114, Folder 4)
      Access restricted until 2072
    - Divinity School Council, 2003 (Box 114, Folder 5)
      Access restricted until 2073
    - Divinity School Council, 2004 (Box 114, Folder 6)
      Access restricted until 2074
    - Divinity School Council, 2005 (Box 114, Folder 7)
      Access restricted until 2075
    - Curriculum Committee, 1986 (Box 114, Folder 8)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 114, Folder 9)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1987 (Box 114, Folder 10)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 114, Folder 11)
      Access restricted until 2058
    - Curriculum Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 114, Folder 12)
      Access restricted until 2059
    - Curriculum Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 114, Folder 13)
      Access restricted until 2060
    - Curriculum Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 114, Folder 14)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 114, Folder 15)
      Access restricted until 2061
    - Curriculum Committee, 1991 (Box 114, Folder 16)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1991-1992 (Box 114, Folder 17)
      Access restricted until 2062
    - Curriculum Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 114, Folder 18)
      Access restricted until 2064
    - Curriculum Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 114, Folder 19)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1994 (Box 114, Folder 20)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1995 (Box 114, Folder 21)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1992 (Box 114, Folder 22)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 114, Folder 23)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 114, Folder 24)
    - Curriculum Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 114, Folder 25)
    - A.M. program, undated (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Annual fund, 1987-1991 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - Baccalaureate service, 1989-1990 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Baccalaureate service, 1991-1992 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Bacalaureate, Chapel, 1993-1994 (Box 115, Folder 5)
    - Black Church Affairs Committee, 1988-1995 (Box 115, Folder 6)
    - Board of Visitors Invitees for fall, 1994-1997 (Box 115, Folder 7)
      Access restricted until 2022
    - Christian Educator's Fellowship (CEF), 1986-1995 (Box 115, Folder 8)
      Access restricted until 2020
    - Visit of Young Bae Chun, visiting scholar, 1997 (Box 115, Folder 9)
    - Clark lectures, 1991-1994 (Box 115, Folder 10)
    - Clark lectures, 1995-1996 (Box 115, Folder 11)
      Access restricted until 2021
    - Computing Advisory Committee, 1989-1994 (Box 115, Folder 12)
    - Communications, 1990-1993 (Box 115, Folder 13)
    - Continuing Education Seminar, 1995 (Box 115, Folder 14)
    - Continuing Education position (for Joe Mann), 1989-1991 (Box 115, Folder 15)
    - Continuing Education, 1991-1995 (Box 115, Folder 16)
    - Convocation Board of Managers, 1989-1997 (Box 115, Folder 17)
    - Closing Convocation, April 27, 1995 (Box 115, Folder 18)
    - Opening Convocation, August 29, 1995 (Box 115, Folder 19)
    - Closing Convocation, April 25, 1996 (Box 115, Folder 20)
    - Opening Convocation, September 3, 1996 (Box 115, Folder 21)
    - Convocation and Pastor's School, 1995-1997 (Box 115, Folder 22)
    - Course of Study School Committee, 1991-1997 (Box 115, Folder 23)
    - CM 100, Fall 1991-1994 (Box 115, Folder 24)
    - Dean Search Committee, 1996-1997 (Box 115, Folder 25)
    - Diaconal Ministry, 1988-1994 (Box 115, Folder 26)
    - Divinity Library, 1990-1993 (Box 115, Folder 27)
    - Divinity School Committees, 1984-1997 (Box 115, Folder 28)
    - Duke/Bonn dinner, Old Trinity Reading Room, September 25, 1995 (Box 115, Folder 29)
    - Faculty dinner/forum plans, Emeritus Professors (Old Trinity), 1992-1993 (Box 115, Folder 30)
    - Faculty/staff and spouse dinner, University Club, August 21, 1994 (Box 115, Folder 31)
    - Faculty dinner; Emereti, Department of Relations, Provost, and President, September 8, 1995 (Box 115, Folder 32)
    - Faculty and staff retreat, 1991-1992 (Box 115, Folder 33)
    - Faculty retreat, August 22, 1994 (Box 115, Folder 34)
    - Faculty retreat, September 15, 1995 (Box 115, Folder 35)
    - Faculty salary information, 1983-1989 (Box 115, Folder 36)
      Includes averages only.
    - Faculty workload, 1991 (Box 115, Folder 37)
    - Field Education, 1990-1994 (Box 115, Folder 38)
    - "Filed" Correspondence with only a note to the dean, 1990-1997 (Box 115, Folder 39)
    - Graduate Program in Religion review (Liz Clark), 1990-1995 (Box 115, Folder 40)
    - Department of Religion, 1986-1993 (Box 115, Folder 41)
    - Graduate Resident Students, 1985-1995 (Box 115, Folder 42)
    - Graduates (M.Div.) and where they are going, 1988-1994 (Box 115, Folder 43)
    - Harkness, Georgia Scholarships, 1992 (Box 115, Folder 44)
    - Inclusive Language Guidelines, 1991-1992 (Box 115, Folder 45)
    - Institute for New Church Pastors, Continuing Education, 1994 (Box 115, Folder 46)
    - International Studies Group, 1983-1996 (Box 115, Folder 47)
    - Luncheon, junior faculty, Sept. 14, 1992 (Box 115, Folder 48)
    - News and notes releases, 1985-1995 (Box 115, Folder 49)
    - Orwond Center Consultation and Rennovation, 1991-1993 (Box 115, Folder 50)
      Access restricted until 2028
    - J.M. Orwond Center, 1990-1995 (Box 115, Folder 51)
    - Amos Ragan Kearns Professorship, Continuing Education, 1987 (Box 115, Folder 52)
    - Lectures Committee, 1991-1994 (Box 115, Folder 53)
    - Locking of Divinity School, 1992-1993 (Box 115, Folder 54)
    - Minority students, alumni, 1989 (Box 115, Folder 55)
    - Orientation letter to new students, 1991-1996 (Box 115, Folder 56)
    - Oxford course, 1995-1996 (Box 115, Folder 57)
    - Pastoral care, 1991, 1994 (Box 115, Folder 58)
    - Peru Exchange Program, Herzog, 1990-1996 (Box 115, Folder 59)
    - Preceptors, 1986-1992 (Box 115, Folder 60)
    - Seminary Day, January 29, 1993 (Box 115, Folder 61)
    - Student Representative Association, 1984-1995 (Box 115, Folder 62)
    - Staff retreat, May 24, 1995 (Box 115, Folder 63)
    - Staff retreat, Inn at Bonnie Brae, May 12, 1994 (Box 115, Folder 64)
    - Student correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 115, Folder 65)
    - Summer program at Duke, 1986 (Box 115, Folder 66)
    - Telethon, 1991-1994 (Box 115, Folder 67)
    - York Chapel, 1958 (Box 115, Folder 68)
    - School Plans Working Drafts, August 15, 1992 (Box 116, Folder 1)
  - Accession UA2015.0017, 2009-2014; UA2015_0017
    Administrative records are restricted for 25 from creation. Access restricted until 2039.
    - #1. Duke Divinity Self-Study, 2015 (Box 117)
    - #2. Duke Divinity Self-Study Appendices, 2015 (Box 117)
    - #3. Current Budget (Box 117)
    - #4. 2013-2014 Audit Budget Management (Box 117)
    - #5. Duke University Managing Documents (Box 117)
    - #6. Duke Div School Bylaws (Portion from Univ. Faculty Handbook) (Box 117)
    - #7. Duke Staff Handbook (Box 117)
    - #8.Divinity School Student Handbook Covenant Code (Box 117)
    - Student Handbook: Policies Procedures (Box 117)
    - #9. Duke Divinity School Board of Visitor Minutes (Box 117)
    - #10. Audited Financial Statements Mgmt Letters, 10/11, 11/12,12/13 (Box 117)
    - #13. Strategic Information Report 2012-13, 2013 (Box 117)
    - #17. 2013 Alumni Survey (Box 117)
    - #18. Duke University 10 Year Strategic Plan 2006-2015 (Box 117)
    - #19. 2009 Targeted Planning for New Divinity Degree Programs (Box 117)
    - #20. Duke Forward Campaign (Divinity Portion) (Box 117)
    - #21. MACP Curriculum Expansion (Box 117)
    - #22. Divinity Degree Assessment Plan (Box 117)
    - #23. Wabash Consultant's Report on ThD 2014 (Box 117)
    - #24. Duke Univ. Strategic Planning Process Launch (Box 117)
    - #29. Application and Enrollment Trend Data (Box 117)
    - #30. Grad Rates, Time to Completion, Placements (Box 117)
    - #31. Divinity Library Collection Development (Box 117)
    - #32. Duke University Library System Agreement YPB for Collection Development Setting (Box 117)
    - #34. Report of University Senate of United Methodist Church (Box 117)
    - #35. Graduate Program in Religion Self-Study (Box 117)
    - #36. ATS Accreditation History (Box 117)
    - Targeted Checklist: Part 1; 2.2-2.9 (Box 117)
    - Targeted Checklist: Part 1; 6.3.1-6.3.8 (Box 117)
    - Targeted Checklist: Part 1; ES6.4.4 v11.A.4/X.A2 (Box 117)
    - Targeted Checklist: Part 2 Cohort Default Rate Document (Box 117)
    - Targeted Checklist: Part 22.7 nos5-8;6.4.1 (Box 117)
    - Circular-A-133 (Box 117)
    - Curriculum Committee Meeting Minutes (Box 117)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes (Box 117)
    - Council Meeting Minutes (Box 117)
    - Closing the Loop: Assessment Charts by degree and resulting curriculum/policy actions (Box 117)
    - Closing the Loop: Assessment Charts by degree and resulting curriculum/policy actions [flashdrive] (Box 117)
    - Entering Student Questionnaire; Graduating Student Questionnaire; Profiles of Participants 1 of 2 (Box 117)
    - Entering Student Questionnaire; Graduating Student Questionnaire; Profiles of Participants 1 of 3, 2 of 2 (Box 117)
  - Accession UA2019.0080, circa 1990s
    - Divinity School building illustrations, planning document (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Architectural drawings (Oversize-folder 2)
  - Accession UA2019.0090
  - Accession UA2019.0091
  - Accession UA2020.0006, undated; 4 boxes
    - OP 16 Swell Chest and Great Chest Drawings, undated; 1 boxes (Box 131)
      Includes 2 rolled drawing plans for the OP 16 Swell Chest, and Great Chest.
      Chapels -- Designs and plans; Organ (Musical Instrument) -- Construction -- History.
- Miscellaneous Memorabilia and Volumes, 1950s-1960s
  - Accession A90-68
    - Dumfries Scrapbook, circa 1965 (Box 108)
  - Accession A2005-0031
    - Graduation Exercises, 1950s-1960s (2 folders) (Box 108)
  - Accession A90-78
    - Bible, Gift of the Class of 1952 (Box 109)
- Audiovisual Materials: Divinity School Interviews and Publicity, 1989-1997
  Original audiovisual media are closed to use; access copies may be requested in advance. Some interviews may be restricted.
  Please contact the Rubenstein Library before coming to use these materials.
  - The Divinity School: Sharing a Vision, 1989 (2 copies, videocassette, use copy must be made for patron use) (Box 110)
  - The Divinity School: A School for the Church, A School for the University, 1995 (videocassette, use copy must be made for patron use) (Box 110)
  - Audiocassette Masters (originals closed to use) (Box 111)
    Interviews may be restricted; please contact the University Archivist for assistance with access.
    - Interview with Donn Michael Farris, 1994 Feb. 17, Mar. 16, Mar. 30, Apr. 6, and May 27 (Box 111)
    - Interview with Florence Blakely, 1994 Apr. 5 (Box 111)
    - Interview with Jerry Campbell, 1994 May 2 (Box 111)
    - Interview with Dean Dennis Campbell, 1994 May 25 (Box 111)
    - Interview with Marty Smith, 1994 June 16 (Box 111)
    - Interview with Roger Loyd, 1994 June 21 (Box 111)
    - Last Lecture: Gayle Felton, 1997 Mar. 7 (Box 111)
    - Last Lecture: Thomas Langford, 1997 Apr. 11 (Box 111)
    - Last Lecture: Dean Dennis Campbell, 1997 Apr. 18 (Box 111)